I'm Always Watching
((オビト：なんだよ　ミナト先生。
俺たちを呼んどいて遅刻かよ。
What the heck...
Minato Sensei tells us to assemble
and he's the one who's late!
しようがねえな。
Give me a break...
You're one to talk!
（カカシ）お前が言うか。
なにを！？
What did you say?
ああん！？
（リン）まあまあ２人とも。
Eh?
Come on, you two...
やんのか　コラ！
フンッ。
Want to do this?
あっ　テメエ今　鼻で笑いやがったな。
だから　どうした？
Hey! Did you just scoff at me?
What of it?
Sorry to keep you waiting.
（ミナト）お待たせ
みんな集まってるね。
You're all here, I see.
ミナト先生！　新しい任務ですか？
Minato Sensei!
Do we have a new mission?!
今日は違うんだ。
Not today.
なんだそれ？
What is that?
They're applications.
志願書だ。
キミたちを中忍に推薦しておいた。
I recommended you three
for promotion to Chunin.
ミナト先生　大好きだよ！
Minato Sensei... You're awesome!
おっと！　気が早いよ。
Hey...
Don't jump the gun.
え？
中忍になるためには試験がある。
Huh?
You have to take
the Chunin Exam first.
え～。
What...
試験は一次　二次　三次とあって
それぞれ　かなりの難関だ。
There are three parts
to the exam
and each one is quite difficult.
チェッ　そうなのか。
Oh... Are you kidding me?
待ち合わせの時刻ひとつ守れない
お前には無理かもな。
You'll never pass since
you can't even make it
to a rendezvous on time.
What did you say?!
なんだと！
ちょっと２人とも。
Hey, you two!
とはいえ　ともに任務を務め→
Anyway...
You've worked together
and earned the right to take
the Chunin Exam.
中忍試験を受ける資格があると
認めたから推薦したんだ。
That's why I recommended you.
ただし　中忍試験は強制ではない。
However, it's not compulsory.
受験するしないは
自分で決めなさい。
Whether you take the exam
or not is entirely up to you.
フフンッ。
もちろん！
I wouldn't miss it...!
CHUNIN EXAM
PART ONE
《なんだよ！
中忍試験っていうから→
Aw man!
This is a Chunin Exam,
忍術か体術かと思ってたら→
so I was expecting stuff like
ninjutsu and taijutsu...
俺のいちばん苦手な
ペーパーテストかよ！》
But this is a written test...
the kind I'm weakest in!
Finished already?
もう終わったのか？
（カカシ）はい。
Yes.
Th-That Kakashi...!
《カ…　カカシのヤツ！
あぁっ！　もうダメだ！》
Aw man, I'm done for...
Huh?!
I'M ALWAYS WATCHING YOU
-RIN
《リン…》
Rin...
キャー！
私　あった！
RIN NOHARA
あった！
やった！
There it is!
I did it!
う…。
KAKASHI HATAKE
（カカシ）まっ　当然でしょ。
Well...
What did you expect?
フンッ！　所詮ペーパーテストじゃねえか！
That was just a written test!
見てろ！　すぐに俺の名前も
見つかるっての！
Just wait and see!
I'll find my name!
END OF LIST
ダメか…。
I guess not...
あっ　オビト！　あれあれ！
Obito!
Look! There!
THE FOLLOWING HAS BEEN
ACCEPTED DUE TO A VACANCY
OBITO UCHIHA
やった～！
補欠合格か。
I did it!
A vacancy, huh...
That's so like you.
オビトらしいな。
なんだと！？
What?!
まあまあ　２人とも。
Come on, you two.
喜んでる暇はねえぜ。
You don't have time
to celebrate!
合格者は　指定の教室に。
If you passed,
go to your assigned classroom!
第二次試験の説明をする。
We'll explain the second part
of the exam.
二次試験は３日後。
Part Two will commence
three days from now.
今度の試験は　実技テストだ。
This will test your physical skills.
お前たちが体得している
体術　忍術のすべてを使い→
Use everything you learned
about taijutsu and ninjutsu...
合格を勝ち取るのだ。
to get through this exam!
よ～し　もらったぜ！
All right! I got this!
ただし　これは
班別の団体対抗戦とする。
However, this test pits
your team against others.
えっ！？　個人戦じゃないのか。
Huh? It's not
an individual competition?!
カカシ　俺たちの足を
引っぱるんじゃねえぜ。
Kakashi! You'd better not
drag us down!
はぁ…。
その言葉
そのままお前に返してやる。
Right back at you.
なに！？
フン。
What?!
２人とも　いい加減にして！
Will you two stop it?!
特に　遅刻するんじゃないぞ。
Especially...don't be late.
フン　わかってらぁ！
I know!
CHUNIN EXAM PART TWO
TEAM COMPETITION
（ヒルゼン）はたけカカシも
受験するんだったな。
Kakashi Hatake is also
participating in the test, right?
Yes, he's on the next team.
はい　この次のチームです。
楽しみだな。
Ah, I'm looking forward to this.
KAKASHI OBITO RIN
GUY EBISU GENMA
IBIKI HAYATE TOKARA
ミナト班　あと５分で時間だが
大丈夫なのか？
Team Minato,
you have five minutes left.
Will he make it?!
はい。
もうすぐ到着すると思います。
Yes! I'm sure he'll be here
in a minute.
もし試験時間に遅れたら
その時点で失格とする。
If time runs out,
you'll be automatically disqualified.
ほらな　俺が言ったとおりだろ。
I knew it! Didn't I tell you?!
リンが甘やかすから
アイツの遅刻グセは直んないんだよ。
You're too easy on him, Rin.
That's why he'll never break
this habit of being late!
大丈夫だよ。　きっと何か大事な
用事があって遅くなってるだけ。
He'll be here.
Something must've happened
to delay him.
試験時間には　間に合うから。
He'll make it in time.
フン　それはどうかな。
I wouldn't be so sure.
HIDDEN LEAF HOSPITAL
はい　飴ちゃんじゃ。
Here, have some candy.
午後３時…　試験開始時間だ。
3:00 pm.
It's time to begin.
クソッ　アイツのせいで…。
Damn it, all because of him!
必ず…。
I know he'll...
遅くなりました！
I'm sorry I'm late!
ほら　オビトは
絶対　来るって言ったでしょ。
See! I told you Obito would make it,
no matter what!
急げ　失格になるぞ。
Hurry, before we're disqualified!
ハァー　ったく。
Oh, boy!
これより　第二次班対抗戦
一次予選を開始する。
We will now begin part two,
the team competition...
Preliminary qualifier!
はじめ！
Begin!
（ガイ）うお～っ！
《火遁　豪火球の…》
Fire Style! Fireball—
CHUNIN EXAM PART THREE
INDIVIDUAL COMPETITION
この間のお返しは
たっぷりさせてもらうからな！
I'm going to have you pay me back
in full for the last time.
この間って…。
The "last time"?
What?!
なに！？　まさか覚えてねえのか？
Don't tell me
you don't remember?!
誰だ　お前は！
恨みをかうような覚えはない！
Who are you?
What did I do to earn
your wrath?!
この～！　バカにしやがって！
Why you—!
Don't take me for a fool!
（リン）頑張って！　オビト！
Do your best, Obito!
よ～し　見ててくれ！
All right... Just watch me!
始め！
えっ？
Begin!
Huh?!
ホアチャー！
勝者　マイト・ガイ！
The winner is Might Guy!
何やってんだか…。
What is he doing?
ぐわっ！
頑張れ！
Do your best!
いけ～！　カカシ！
Go...!
Kakashi!
Stop!
そこまで！　勝者　はたけカカシ！
The winner is Kakashi Hatake!
やった！
He did it!
一発で中忍試験をクリアするなんて
やっぱりカカシは　すごいよ！
You passed the Chunin Exam
on your first try.
Kakashi, you're amazing!
Isn't he, Obito?
ねっ　オビト！
フン！
あっ…。
Humph.
オビト…。
Obito...
（オビト）はぁ…。
こんなとこにいたんだ！
So this is where you were.
うわっ…　なんだ　リンか。
O-Oh, it's you, Rin.
カカシが受かるのは当然だけど
私たちもできるよ　きっと！
It's only natural
that Kakashi passed.
But we can too, I know it!
来年の試験　頑張りましょ！
Let's practice hard
for next year!
でもよ　カカシ見てると
なんだか　やる気が出なくて。
But it's hard to get motivated
after watching Kakashi...
なに言ってるの！
What are you saying?!
火影になるんでしょ。
You're going to be Hokage, right?
私が　ちゃんと見てるから！
I'm always watching you!
(ああ！))
Yeah!
((オビト？
Obito?
やったぜ！　俺も中忍だ！
I did it!
I'm a Chunin now!
おめでとう！
フン！
Congratulations!
あとで公園の桜の木の下に来て。
Meet me later at the park
under the cherry tree.
《今日こそ　リンに
俺の本当の気持を…》
Today for sure...
I'm going to tell Rin
how I feel about her!
遅れて　ごめ～ん！
いやいや…。
Sorry I'm late...
– No...
– Everyone!
みんな！
みんな？
Everyone?
え？
Why? Uh, Why...
なんで？
なんで　みんな　いるんだよ？
Why is everyone here?!
お祝いの相談をするから
集まってもらったの。
I asked them to come
to discuss the gift.
えっ　お祝いの相談って？
Huh? What gift?!
今度　カカシが上忍に
就任するでしょ？
Well, Kakashi is being promoted
to Jonin.
だから　同期のみんなで何か
プレゼントしようって。
So, we're going to...
give him a present.
CLASS PROJECT
GIFT FOR KAKASHI'S PROMOTION
TO JONIN
(TOP SECRET MISSION)
カカシが上忍に？
Kakashi's a Jonin?
あれ　オビト知らなかったの？
Oh? Didn't you know, Obito?
同期の私たちにとっても→
It's something to be proud of
as his classmates.
自慢のたねでしょ。
は　はぁ…。
Yeah...
ねぇ　何したら　カカシ喜ぶと思う？
What do you think
Kakashi would like?
そうねぇ　アイツのことだから…。
Well... Since we're talking about him,
it should be
something useful.
これから行うのは実戦訓練だ。
Now we'll do combat training.
訓練だからと油断していると
命にもかかわる。
It might just be training,
but if you're not alert,
it can be fatal. Understood?
いいね？
（３人）はい！
– Yes!
あっ！　いや　まぁ…
ざっと　こんなもんさ。
Well...I guess that's it!
左手　みせて。
Show me your left hand!
いやぁ　こんなの
どうってことねえから。
Hey, it's nothing...
ただのかすり傷だから
ツバつけとけば治るって。
It's just a scrape.
A little spit will take care of it.
いいから　みせなさい！
Whatever! Just show me!
ちょっと　ヘマしちまった。
I messed up...
目に砂が入っちまって…。
I got some sand in my eyes and...
ハハッ！　男にゃ　傷の一つや二つ→
A scar or two on a man
is a badge of courage!
体に刻んどかなきゃ
はくがつかねえし→
ちょうど　はくをつけとく
頃合いだと思ってよ。
I was just thinking how
I needed that.
だから　こんな傷…。
So this wound's...
痛っ！！
Ouch!
（リン）強がって傷を隠しても　ダメ。
Don't act tough and
hide your wounds.
ちゃんと見てんだから。
I'm always watching you.
オビトは　火影になるって
私に約束した。
You promised me that you would
become Hokage, Obito.
いい？
私だって　この戦争を止めたい。
Listen, I want to stop this war too.
世界を救いたいと
本気で思ってるよ。
I really want to save the world.
だから　オビトのこと　そばで
しっかり見守るって決めたの。
So I decided to stick by your side
and watch over you.
あなたを救うことは
世界を救うのと同じなんでしょ？
You told me saving you
was the same as saving
the world, remember?
うん…。
Yeah...
私が見張ってるってことは→
Since I'm keeping an eye on you,
もう　なんにも
隠し事はできないよ。
you can't hide anything
from me anymore.
うん…　うん…。
Okay! Okay!
（リン）頑張れ　オビト！
Go for it, Obito!
火影になって　かっこよく
世界を救うとこ見せてね！
Become Hokage and show me
how you'll save the world.
それも約束だよ。
That's another promise!
(行こう))
Let's go!
（ナルト）お前　仲間の思いや思い出を
全部　捨てるって→
You...
You told Kakashi Sensei
you would throw away
all your memories and feelings
about your comrades.
カカシ先生に言ってたみてぇだけど→
十尾の人柱力になって　ソイツに
乗っ取られそうになったとき…。
But when you became
the Ten Tails' Jinchuriki
and were about to
be taken over by it...
((オビト：あ～っ！))
それが嫌で　十尾を押さえ込もうと
したんじゃねえのかよ？
Didn't you try to suppress
the Ten Tails
because you didn't want that?
((うわぁ！！))
十尾に勝って
それを自分で操れたのは→
The reason why you beat
the Ten Tails and could control it
今までのことを
捨てたくねえって→
was because you stood firm
on not throwing away the past
踏ん張って
自分のままでいたからだろ。
and stayed yourself, right?
お前　やっぱり
父ちゃんも　カカシ先生も→
You just couldn't throw out
the memories of
my dad, Kakashi Sensei or
this Rin person, could you?
リンって人の思い出も
捨てられなかったんじゃねえのか。
だから　十尾の人柱力になっても→
That's how you could stay Obito
even after you became
the Ten Tails' Jinchuriki.
オビトのままでいられたんだろう？
違うかよ？
Am I wrong?
けど　みんなを巻き込んで→
But dragging everyone with you
onto your path
お前の道を
このまま突き進むのは→
許されることじゃねえ！
and continuing on it
won't be allowed!
こっちの道へ来て
うちはオビトとして→
I'm bringing you back
as Obito Uchiha...
木ノ葉の忍として
きっちり罪を償ってもらう。
as a shinobi of the Hidden Leaf...
and you're going to atone
for your sins.
何もかもから
逃げようとしやがって！
You tried to run away
from every single thing.
((その先に待っているのは
お前も　よく知る→
The only thing that awaits you...
is your personal nightmare.
最も恐ろしい…。
孤独だ！
Solitude!
現実にいる必要が　どこにある？
So why keep living in reality?
(いい加減　こっちへ来い　ナルト！))
Now come join us, Naruto!
リンって人が生きてたら
きっと　こう言っただろうな。
I bet this Rin person would say this
if she were still alive...
強がって自分を隠すなって。
Don
ちゃんと見てんだからってよ。
お前は　お前だ　この野郎！
逃げんな！
お前こそ　こっちへ来い！
オビト！
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！　にっぽんの歌』。
（松丸）今回は特別に
島倉千代子さんの→
ヒットメドレーからスタートします。